<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-12-11T17:36:11+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs//</id><title type="html">Hobart Hackerspace Inc.</title><subtitle>We are Hobart Hackerspace!
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Grant money has been spent!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/12/11/grant-money.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grant money has been spent!" /><published>2016-12-11T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2016-12-11T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/12/11/grant-money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/12/11/grant-money.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/hhs/assets/new-tools.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Tools!&quot; title=&quot;New Tools!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tanya McLachlan-Troup and Mark Pearson have kindly donated their time to go and spend our $3000 grant money, awarded by The Mens Shed Association.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We applied for this grant around a year ago and it was granted a few months ago. We have finally got around to spending the money, and we are celebrating by having a BBQ next Wednesday (14 Dec 2016). We want you to join us to celebrate the purchasing of the new tools with the grant money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vegan sausages and gluten-free bread will be available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sausages are $1 and cans are $1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So please come along to help celebrate and check out the tools!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Craig Marshall</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A lathe for Hobart hackerspace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/11/02/new-lathe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A lathe for Hobart hackerspace" /><published>2016-11-02T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2016-11-02T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/11/02/new-lathe</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/11/02/new-lathe.html">&lt;p&gt;We have been very fortunate with donations to Hobart hackerspace. Recently, we had a donation of a sherline 3” precision lathe. ( thanks, Ray! )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This machine was covered in the dust of ages, but the parts are all in very good condition. So, being hackers, the first thing we did was to pull our new machine apart. A bit of a polish on the brass, and a bit of oil in the moving parts, and away it went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lathe is quite small and simple to use, but remember - it is a power tool. Remember to wear safety glasses. Think about what you are doing. If in doubt, ask!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>fairly.sirius</name></author><summary type="html">We have been very fortunate with donations to Hobart hackerspace. Recently, we had a donation of a sherline 3” precision lathe. ( thanks, Ray! )</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Delta Printer Test</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/09/05/hhs-delta-printer-test.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Delta Printer Test" /><published>2016-09-05T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-09-05T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/09/05/hhs-delta-printer-test</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/09/05/hhs-delta-printer-test.html">&lt;div class=&quot;xwrapper&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;h_iframe&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/uMHtf_U0w_0?color=white&amp;amp;theme=light&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>jjbarrows</name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mon/Wed internet access</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/08/03/mon-wed-internet.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mon/Wed internet access" /><published>2016-08-03T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-08-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/08/03/mon-wed-internet</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/08/03/mon-wed-internet.html">&lt;p&gt;Most mondays and wednesdays someone plugs something either misconfigured or malicious into the network which breaks it. please check your devices.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jjbarrows</name></author><summary type="html">Most mondays and wednesdays someone plugs something either misconfigured or malicious into the network which breaks it. please check your devices.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Live Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/04/27/live-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Live Blog" /><published>2016-04-27T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2016-04-27T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/04/27/live-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/04/27/live-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;Hi and welcome to my first live update from a Weekly Meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a bit of tinkering going on tonight as well as some visitors being shown around the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brian is working on “Repairing” an old british electric beater.  Looks interesting and will be great to see it working at another meeting.  Maybe he can mix us some nice batter to make some donuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the Mark’s is working on a homebuilt Infrared thermometer using and Arduino Nano with a infrared temprature sensor (Freetronics) and a nice OLED display from a kickstarter (See, some things do actually eventuate from Kickstarter).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BREAKING NEWS&lt;/strong&gt; - As I am typing this the space’s new 3D Printer has just turned up.  Looks like a Sunday Session coming up. The new printer is a Duinotech TL-4100 Delta Kit.  Stay tuned for more updates on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also looking at one of the new mini CNC’s.  A very nice looking device which will set you back about $650 from Ebay.  More details will follow in a post later this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David is busy engraving a logo onto a chopping board for a prize.  At least we have some use coming to the Laser Cutter.  We are currently looking into upgrading the laser tube on this so it should be more usefull soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have some general tidying up going on around the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is good to see a buzz of activity going on at the moment.  So heading into the cooler months the Hackspace seems to be picking up again which is good to see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So tell your friends and get them coming along to join in the journey, plus no doubt get into some interesting conversations about what we are going to try and computerised next (yes we will eventually finish the knitting machine).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So see you next week with the next live blog and hopefully some other updates through the week.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alkaline</name></author><summary type="html">Hi and welcome to my first live update from a Weekly Meeting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">3D Printer Fundraising</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/03/13/3d-printer-fundraising.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="3D Printer Fundraising" /><published>2016-03-13T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2016-03-13T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/03/13/3d-printer-fundraising</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2016/03/13/3d-printer-fundraising.html">&lt;p&gt;The 3D printer at Hobart Hackerspace Inc has seen better days. It’s now more than 3 years old and has been flaky for some time. We’d love to raise $2000-$2500 to buy an awesome SLA printer for our members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the link if you would like to donate: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.givenow.com.au/hobarthackerspace3dprinter&quot;&gt;https://www.givenow.com.au/hobarthackerspace3dprinter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>cm</name></author><summary type="html">The 3D printer at Hobart Hackerspace Inc has seen better days. It’s now more than 3 years old and has been flaky for some time. We’d love to raise $2000-$2500 to buy an awesome SLA printer for our members.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hackerspace WoW! (Week of workshops)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/06/19/hackerspace-wow.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hackerspace WoW! (Week of workshops)" /><published>2015-06-19T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2015-06-19T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/06/19/hackerspace-wow</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/06/19/hackerspace-wow.html">&lt;p&gt;Hobart Hackerspace Week of Workshops, now over two weeks :P&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have GovHack and we have our own lives and wives/husbands to deal with, so this time our Week of Workshops has a few breaks in the middle, but you still get all the excellence of learning new things from people who are really no smarter than you. Don’t you love the honesty? You know it’s true when most of these workshops are being run by Shane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For financial members it’s all free, non-members $10 (excluding the Wednesday evening session 8th Jul which is open to the public)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mon-29-jun-2015---cnc---gcode&quot;&gt;Mon 29 Jun 2015 - CNC - gcode&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know what gcode is? Can you understand what these machine instructions are?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to have a session dedicated to the language of CNC machines the world over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 - 9pm (no prerequisites)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tue-30-jun-2015--cnc---cam&quot;&gt;Tue 30 Jun 2015- CNC - CAM&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This session will cover basic tooling and material cutting theory, and how we go about generating a gcode file from a CAD drawing. We will look at the different ways of milling a 3D surface, and how to generate simple files for the CNC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 - 9pm (prerequisites - either a CNC tooling or gcode workshop)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;mon-6th-jul-2015---cad-primitives&quot;&gt;Mon 6th Jul 2015 - CAD (Primitives)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the very entry level FreeCAD course for people who want to draw basic components using primitive shapes. It’s like the LEGO of CAD, blocks stacked upon each other but at the end of it all you have a design ready for the 3D printer or CNC&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 - 9pm (no prerequisites - byo computer with a current version of FreeCAD installed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;tue-7th-jul-2015---cad-draft&quot;&gt;Tue 7th Jul 2015 - CAD (Draft)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this session we will look at more advanced features of freeCAD, such as using constraints to shift a measured or drawn complex design in to a series of drafts and then turn them in to a 3D object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 - 9pm (no prerequisites but the primitives course may be beneficial - byo computer with a current version of FreeCAD installed)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wed-8th-jul-2015---celestial-navigation&quot;&gt;Wed 8th Jul 2015 - Celestial navigation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yep, no kidding.. This is going to be a short session where we’ll ask the question, “how did those dutch explorers get most of the way around the world in the 1600s?” Have you ever wondered? Not all of them crashed like Dirk Hartog, but how? The answer is surprisingly simple&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8 - 9pm (no prerequisites)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;thu-9th-jul-2015---attiny-the-tiny-soution-to-everything&quot;&gt;Thu 9th Jul 2015 - ATTINY, the tiny soution to everything&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you need to flash a light, respond to an input or do some simple repetitive task. The ATTINY is a great replacement for many analog circuits and can be programmed to do all the things you need and more. We’re going to look at the chip, the architecture and some simple programs to replace the need for things like 555 (timer) circuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 - 9pm  (no prerequisites - byo compuer with arduino IDE installed)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Shane</name></author><summary type="html">Hobart Hackerspace Week of Workshops, now over two weeks :P</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Delta Printer Update</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/03/25/delta-printer-update.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Delta Printer Update" /><published>2015-03-25T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2015-03-25T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/03/25/delta-printer-update</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/03/25/delta-printer-update.html">&lt;p&gt;Well, it has been a while since I posted an update on the progress of the Printer, well, it seems I got distracted :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past few months I have managed to learn a lot about the Laser Cutter and have been proud to be part of the team helping to get it back in action.  You should see some improvements in that very soon as we have new mirrors arriving soon and progress is happening every week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the printer, the initial design had some minor flaws, IE, I shouldn’t have rushed the designs as I made a few mistakes in alignment which caused all the problems.  As such I have spent quite a bit more time re doing the mounts and hopefully I should be able to start printing them very soon.  This along with some CNC’d parts should get my 3D printer back online in the next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for some more updates soon and hopefully I will get cracking on a weekly run down on the wednesday night meetings as well for those that couldn’t make it but would like to keep up with whats happening in the space.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alkaline</name></author><summary type="html">Well, it has been a while since I posted an update on the progress of the Printer, well, it seems I got distracted :).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Social Night - Returning for 2015</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/01/06/social-night-returning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Social Night - Returning for 2015" /><published>2015-01-06T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2015-01-06T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/01/06/social-night-returning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/01/06/social-night-returning.html">&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone. Just a quick message to let you know that Social Night’s are returning for 2015 from this Wednesday, 7 January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&quot;https://hobarthackerspace.org.au/civicrm/event/info?reset=1&amp;amp;id=3&quot;&gt;find all the details here&lt;/a&gt; for our first one of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Social Night’s are a perfect opportunity for non-members to visit, check our the space and the people that make it what it is. Visitors are most welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to a massive 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers
Craig Clark
HHS Vice President and wannabe maker! :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>craigclark</name></author><summary type="html">Hello everyone. Just a quick message to let you know that Social Night’s are returning for 2015 from this Wednesday, 7 January.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Closing in on the finish line</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/01/04/closing-in-on-the-finish-line.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Closing in on the finish line" /><published>2015-01-04T00:00:00+11:00</published><updated>2015-01-04T00:00:00+11:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/01/04/closing-in-on-the-finish-line</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/hhs/2015/01/04/closing-in-on-the-finish-line.html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I can see a light at the end of the tunnel.  After a nice holiday break I managed to spend a few hours down at hackspace watching my last pieces printing on the MakerBot.  3 sets of rail guides later I now have a fully assembled printer :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next step on the path is to get the heatbed and hotend all mounted an ready to go and finalise the mounting of the electonics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a bit of a work session this weekend I have assembled all off the electronics and tested them with the modified ATX power supply.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So hopefully by the end of the week I will have a working 3D Delta Printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fo those interested in seeing it alive I should be working on it as normal at the next Wednesday Social Night and hopefully making it move :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will post some pictures later.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>alkaline</name></author><summary type="html">Well, I can see a light at the end of the tunnel.  After a nice holiday break I managed to spend a few hours down at hackspace watching my last pieces printing on the MakerBot.  3 sets of rail guides later I now have a fully assembled printer :)</summary></entry></feed>
